[Music]
[音乐]
okay I think I think we can start we are
好吧，我想我想我们可以开始
like two minutes after the schedule what
大概两分钟之后
I think it's I think it's okay good
我觉得很好
morning everyone
大家早上好
I hope you're having good time in at the
希望您在这里玩得开心
conference and in the Barcelona in
会议并在巴塞罗那举行
general and to be fair like I mean
一般，公平地说，我的意思是
Barcelona is such a nice place that it
巴塞罗那是一个很棒的地方
it's difficult to not have a good time
很难没有美好的时光
here I spoke recently with my colleague
我最近在这里与同事交谈
that I will give this talk about Java
我会讲有关Java的内容
relational persistence and he told me
关系持久性，他告诉我
like oh my God why can't you tell about
像哦，我的天哪，你为什么不能讲
something that is actually cool modern
实际上很酷的东西
like you know maybe no sequel
就像你知道也许没有续集
microservices and so on so maybe let's
微服务等等，所以也许让我们
follow his way of thinking a little bit
遵循他的思维方式
more or less 10 years ago like 99 10
大约10年前像99 10
years ago the the no sequel movement
多年前的无续集运动
started and there was a first no sequel
开始，没有第一个续集
meetup in San Francisco and more or less
旧金山聚会或多或少
like everything starts in San Francisco
就像一切始于旧金山
so we can put it like a pretty good date
所以我们可以说是一个很好的约会
and I'm wondering how many of you work
我想知道你们中有多少人在工作
in the business like professionally for
像专业人士一样从事业务
more than 10 years if you could raise
如果您可以养育超过10年
your hand just with bubi
你的手只跟布比
ok I think it's like more or less 50 50
好吧，我想大概是50 50
like 50 percent I find it quite
像50％的人觉得
interesting because when I when I
有趣，因为当我当我
started working and I was at my first
开始工作，我刚开始
conference in 2008 that at that time
当时的2008年会议
when someone had like 2 to 3 years of
当某人有2至3年的
experience he was already qualifying to
他已经有资格参加
be a senior because the the whole
因为整体
community was quite some immature but
社区还有些不成熟，但是
back to the back to the meetup so the
回到聚会，所以
meetup was announcing the end of our
见面会宣布我们的终结
DBMS era maybe right and one of the
DBMS时代也许是正确的，也是其中之一
quote from this meetup was that the
这次聚会的报价是
relational databases give you just too
关系数据库也给您
much they force you to twist your object
他们迫使你扭曲你的物体
data to fit into our DBMS and no sequel
数据适合我们的DBMS，无后遗症
just give you what you need and I think
只要给你你需要的东西，我想
everyone who worked with relational
每个与关系部门合作的人
databases or I mean especially end with
数据库或我的意思是特别以
with document let's say base databases
与文档一起说基本数据库
kind of know what it means and the two
知道这是什么意思，两者
main problems that people were seeing
人们看到的主要问题
with relational databases was that they
关系数据库是
were not really scalable and they were
没有真正的可扩展性，它们是
inflexible meaning we had to define this
僵化的意思，我们必须定义这个
fixed schema the schema was really hard
固定模式，模式真的很难
and these were like the two main
这些就像两个主要的
concerns that no sequel databases were
担心没有续集数据库
addressing at that time and it was 10 10
当时的地址是10 10
years ago so it was already quite a
年前，所以已经是相当
while but a lot of things have changed
虽然很多事情都变了
since then in the in the relational
从那以后在关系
database space and I will just pick I
数据库空间，我会选择我
picked like three databases or maybe
像三个数据库一样选择
even two-and-a-half that there are the
甚至有两个半的时间
most popular the most popular ones that
最流行的
they are open source I didn't work too
他们是开源的，我也没工作
much with Oracle so I will not say too
与Oracle息息相关，所以我也不会说
much about Oracle in general but the
一般而言，有关Oracle的内容很多，但是
Postgres especially that's that's my
Postgres特别是那是我的
favorite database over the over the last
过去最喜欢的数据库
years they really developed a lot of
几年他们确实发展了很多
improvements in the let's let's say the
让我们说说改进
core engine so back in the days whenever
核心引擎让我们回到过去
you wanted to make a change in the
您想对
database structure like adding a new
数据库结构，例如添加新的
column changing the types and so on it
更改类型的列等等
was very likely that you would end up in
你很有可能最终会陷入
the table lock meaning that your
表锁意味着您
database will not be able to either read
数据库将无法读取
or write from the particular table or a
或从特定的表格或
particular row it really depends and of
它真正取决于的特定行
course for the applications that we
当然，我们的应用程序
often build nowadays that have like
时下经常建造有
millions of consumers thousands of
数以百万计的消费者
requests per second like having this
每秒的请求数
table lock meaning that the requests
表锁意味着请求
will start piling up and basically that
将开始堆积，基本上
everything will start to explode and
一切都会开始爆炸，
that's the problem that they almost
那就是他们几乎要面对的问题
eliminate it so nowadays it's quite
消除它，所以今天很
unlikely that you will get a table log
您不太可能会获得表日志
even when you create an index you can
即使创建索引，您也可以
create index concurrently so that the
同时创建索引，以便
index is being created in the background
在后台创建索引
they also introduced the JSON data types
他们还介绍了JSON数据类型
that it like directly addresses the
就像直接解决
let's say the no sequel databases
假设没有续集数据库
advantages so now not only you have the
优势，所以现在不仅您拥有
all the benefits of having the
具有的所有好处
relational structure but also if you
关系结构，如果你
need to store some sort of unstructured
需要存储某种非结构化的
data you can put it into the JSON column
您可以将其放入JSON列的数据
time type and you don't have to put it
时间类型，您不必放
just as a string this is actually the
就像一个字符串，实际上是
the structure that you can both index
你们都可以索引的结构
and you can query like using the fields
您可以像使用字段一样进行查询
they also have a support for XML that I
他们也有对XML的支持，
haven't personal use they also support
还没有个人使用，他们也支持
geospatial queries and full-text search
地理空间查询和全文搜索
the full-text search maybe is not as
全文搜索可能不像
impressive as the Lucene index and let's
令人印象深刻的Lucene指数，让我们
say the elastic search but still I mean
说弹性搜索，但我的意思仍然是
it's totally sufficient
完全足够
many use cases so prosperous basically
许多用例基本上如此繁荣
like became a really really serious
变得非常认真
feature-rich database my sequel back in
功能丰富的数据库，我的续集
the days was considered like let's say
日子就像我们说的
that the database for a wordpress so not
该数据库的WordPress的，所以不是
for serious stuff but over the years
对于严重的东西，但多年来
they also evolved so now they have like
他们也进化了，所以现在他们喜欢
this the features that we expect like to
这是我们期望的功能
be a standard that they have foreign
成为外国人的标准
keys AC transactions they also support
他们还支持关键的AC交易
JSON and it's used in lots of serious
JSON，它在很多严肃的情况下都被使用
projects of Pinterest is based on my
Pinterest的项目基于我的
sequel or at least it used to be and
续集，或者至少曾经是
then we have this this these were the
然后我们有这个，这些是
two databases and now we have the half
两个数据库，现在我们有了一半
because AWS Aurora is not exactly the
因为AWS Aurora并非完全
let's say the completely different
假设完全不同
database but it's rather an engine that
数据库，但它是一个引擎
it's built on the or maybe it's an it's
它建立在或也许是
a it's a database that it stays
它是一个数据库
compatible with either post dress or my
与邮政礼服或我的兼容
sequel and they advertise it as the
续集，他们将其作为
relational database for the cloud and
云的关系数据库和
all the other cloud providers have
所有其他云提供商都拥有
something similar that I haven't worked
我没用过的类似东西
with but able a AWS Aurora address is
具有但能够提供AWS Aurora地址的功能是
very nicely the scalability issues of
很好的可扩展性问题
relational databases and I mean one
关系数据库，我的意思是一个
thing is that it's they claimed at least
事实是，他们至少声称
that it's much much faster like 10 times
快了十倍
faster than my sequel the benchmarks
比我的续集基准测试更快
show different things but it all depends
显示不同的东西，但这全都取决于
how you manipulate the benchmark but
您如何操作基准，但是
there are not two nice ways to scale the
没有两个很好的方法来扩展
Aurora database and one is you can scale
Aurora数据库，一个就是可以扩展
it up so basically you can use the
这样基本上可以使用
bigger instance which is nothing really
更大的实例，真的不算什么
new but considering that you can scale
新功能，但考虑到您可以扩展
it up up to the machine that runs on 120
直到运行120的机器为止
you CPUs and 4 terabytes of RAM I mean
您的CPU和4 TB RAM
you have to admit that this is a pretty
你必须承认这是一个漂亮的
nice note I mean this is something that
好的说明，我的意思是，这是
can handle quite a lot but you can also
可以处理很多，但您也可以
scale it out so you can put more read
扩展它，以便您可以阅读更多
replicas and that means that all the
复制品，这意味着所有
reads go to read replicas and you can
读取去读取副本，您可以
have like as many of them as you want
随心所欲
probably there is a limit and so for
可能有限制，因此
many use cases that's also sufficient
许多用例也足够了
and they also introduced the server last
他们最后还介绍了服务器
version meaning that the the let's say
版本的意思是说
they assigned compute power including
他们分配了计算能力，包括
your bill like it scales depending on
您的帐单比例取决于
your traffic
你的流量
so these were the the two issues that
所以这是两个问题
were the main problem with relational
是关系的主要问题
databases and they have been kind of
数据库，它们一直是
addressed until now but for me the most
到现在为止，但对我来说最多
interesting and the biggest problem of
有趣和最大的问题
no sequel databases is that or maybe the
没有续集数据库是，或者也许
benefit of relational databases is that
关系数据库的好处是
the relational databases are much more
关系数据库更多
forgiving if you use no sequel databases
如果您不使用任何续集数据库，请原谅
and just to just to clarify that I'm a
只是为了澄清我是
big fan of no sequel databases in
没有续集数据库的忠实拥护者
general multiple different databases but
通用多个不同的数据库，但是
they come with a significant drawback so
他们有一个很大的缺点，所以
usually when you work with no sequel
通常在没有续集的情况下
databases you have to structure you have
您必须构建的数据库
to design the dis implicit schema and
设计非隐式架构，并
for the particular use case for the
针对特定的用例
particular feature for particular access
特定访问权限的特定功能
patterns and what may happen is that the
模式，可能发生的是
requirement change over the time or the
随时间变化的需求或
access patterns change and then you
访问模式发生变化，然后您
suddenly may end up in the state when
突然可能会变成这种状态
the your sequel no sequel structure does
你的续集没有续集结构
not fit anymore and then you have to
不再适合，然后您必须
restructure it but restructuring the the
重组它，但重组
no sequel databases is not an easy job
没有续集数据库并非易事
because there's just no support for it
因为没有支持
so usually you have to either script it
因此通常您必须编写脚本
or find another workaround in worst case
或在最坏的情况下找到其他解决方法
scenario you may and you may be even not
可能会发生的情况，甚至可能不会发生
able to restructure it because you may
能够重组它，因为您可能
be lost already some data but with the
已经丢失了一些数据，但随着
relational databases we have the all the
关系数据库，我们拥有所有
power of sequel so whatever something
续集的力量，所以无论如何
changes we can very easily using sequel
改变我们可以很容易地使用续集
language having the guarantees of sequel
具有续集保证的语言
language we can basically restructure
我们可以基本重组的语言
the data shall we shuffle it to
数据我们将其洗牌到
different tables so I very like like a
不同的桌子，所以我非常喜欢
lot this tweet from Lucas either
还是来自卢卡斯的这条推文
that I mean sequel is not going anywhere
我的意思是续集一无所获
anywhere relational databases are not
没有关系数据库的任何地方
going anywhere
去任何地方
they were valid for last 20 years and
它们在过去20年内有效，并且
I'm pretty sure they will be valid for
我很确定他们将对
for next 20 years
未来20年
my name is matt eval Kovac I'm an
我的名字是马特·埃瓦尔·科瓦奇，我是
independent consultant meaning I work as
独立顾问，意味着我是
a freelancer working with spring since I
自从我成为 Spring 的自由职业者
mean using spring technologies since
意味着自从开始使用Spring 技术
2007 and
2007年
recently the most of the projects I work
最近我工作的大部分项目
with are based on cotton and most of
与基于棉花和大多数
them run on AWS I also contribute to
它们在AWS上运行，我也为
open source project projects and it's
开源项目项目，它是
these are usually the sprink projects
这些通常是洒水项目
this is like the one of the recent
这就像最近的
change that I did it's not maybe
改变我所做的可能不是
extremely impressive but whenever I find
非常令人印象深刻，但只要我发现
something that I find a bug or something
我发现错误的东西
that maybe could be improved then at
那也许可以改善
least I try and it doesn't happen very
至少我尝试过，并不会发生
often but I encourage you to do so
通常，但我鼓励您这样做
whenever you have time for last year I
每当你有时间去年
spent most of the time with my son
花了大部分时间陪我儿子
I took the six months parental leave and
我休了六个月的育儿假，
I know that many people cannot really
我知道很多人不能真正
afford it but if only if you are I would
负担得起，但只要你愿意，我就会
strongly encourage you to do so because
强烈建议您这样做，因为
this really builds the bounce with
这确实建立了反弹
children a lot I also run a YouTube
孩子很多，我也经营YouTube
channel called Spring Academy where I
我叫Spring Academy的频道
post videos tutorials about spring it
发布有关spring it的视频教程
the videos are at least like more or
这些视频至少像更多或
less like once a month or but it goes
不像一个月一次，但是
good because it's not I mean it's quite
好，因为不是，我的意思是
time-consuming but if you are into
耗时，但是如果您喜欢
spring and you enjoy that say watching
Spring ，你喜欢说看
Josh long spring tips this is something
乔什（Josh）漫长的 Spring 提示这是什么
that we can say that was a similar or
我们可以说那是类似的
it's aiming to be as good as spring tips
它的目标是与 spring 技巧 一样好
but back to our topic
回到我们的话题
so the the talked topic of the talk is
所以谈话的话题是
the state of the relational databases
关系数据库的状态
sorry the state of the Java relational
对不起Java关系的状态
resistance and there is a lot of things
抵抗和很多事情
going on in this space there are lots of
在这个空间里有很多
interesting frameworks lots of
有趣的框架很多
interesting technologies and the idea is
有趣的技术，想法是
that I will introduce these technologies
我将介绍这些技术
to you so that later on if you like
给你，以便以后如果你喜欢
either start a new project or even work
开始一个新项目甚至工作
with your existing project you will be
与您现有的项目，您将
able to make better decisions like which
能够做出更好的决定，例如
technologies to choose from but before
可供选择的技术
we do I would like to clarify some
我们要做的是澄清一些
basics because I saw the discussion on
基础知识，因为我看到了关于
Twitter between two Java champions like
两个Java冠军之间的Twitter，例如
if hibernate is an alternative to JDBC
如果休眠是JDBC的替代方法
so that like a very quick introduction
这样就像一个快速的介绍
how these things actually work so it
这些东西实际上是如何工作的
always starts with a with a database it
总是以一个数据库开头
doesn't really matter which database it
哪个数据库并不重要
is and on the other side there is our
在另一边是我们
application this the application works
应用程序，这个应用程序的工作原理
talks to the data
与数据对话
over network and each of these databases
通过网络以及这些数据库中的每一个
use a little bit different
使用有点不同
wired protocol so we of course don't
有线协议，所以我们当然不
want to learn like our goat so low level
想像我们的山羊一样学习
we want to write sequel queries and in
我们要编写续集查询
order to do it it goes all through the
为了做到这一点，它贯穿了整个过程
JDBC drivers so the JDBC is a standard
JDBC驱动程序，因此JDBC是标准的
there's like set of interfaces that each
每组都有一组相似的接口
of these providers on the right-hand
这些供应商在右边
side have to implement to be compliant
方面必须实施以符合要求
with JDBC so then we take this jar into
使用JDBC，然后我们将这个jar放入
our applications and we write the code
我们的应用程序，我们编写代码
that looks something like this this is
看起来像这样
not exactly the code that we write at
不完全是我们编写的代码
least I haven't seen this kind of cult
至少我没有见过这种崇拜
in production because obviously this is
在生产中，因为显然这是
way way too low-level I mean you don't
太低级了，我的意思是你不
want I mean this is it asks for making
想要我的意思是这是要求
bugs right but there's nothing wrong
错误是正确的，但没有错
about the JDBC itself what we usually do
关于JDBC本身，我们通常会做什么
is we think in objects write Java is
我们认为在对象中写Java是
object oriented language we are very
面向对象的语言，我们非常
used to work with with entities and this
曾经与实体合作
is more or less the code that we want to
是我们想要的代码
write so we put in our application JP a
写，所以我们把我们的应用程序JP a
provider which in most cases is
在大多数情况下是
hibernate anybody uses different JP
休眠任何人使用不同的JP
provider here there are two hands okay
提供者这里有两只手还可以
so it means that it's I don't know 5%
所以这意味着我不知道5％
maybe it's something like that I
也许是那样的我
personally never had a chance I'm not
我个人从来没有机会
saying that high Bernese is the best by
说高伯尔尼语是最好的
just it just became such a such a
只是它变得如此如此
standard right so it works in a way that
标准权利，因此它的工作方式
there is a hibernate inside our
我们里面有一个冬眠
application there's also the JDBC driver
应用程序还有JDBC驱动程序
and whenever you do something with the
以及每当您对
hibernate it always goes through the
冬眠它总是经历
JDBC so so JDBC is still working under
JDBC，因此JDBC仍在
the hood even when you use hibernate
引擎盖，即使您使用冬眠
so for the rest of the talk I will
所以在接下来的演讲中，我将
actually use JPA and hibernate and I
实际使用JPA和休眠，我
think always about the same thing and I
总是想着同一件事，我
would like to start with JP a so JP most
想从JP开始，所以JP最
of the people whenever like whatever
无论何时何地
project stars the resolution the
该项目为解决方案加注星标
database they just take JP a this is a
数据库，他们只是JP，这是一个
standard everyone knows it and it's
标准每个人都知道，这是
simple all right at least it's easy to
简单好吧，至少很容易
start with and I don't think actually
首先，我不认为
that JP a is simple I think that JP a is
JP a很简单，我认为JP a是
it's super complex if we look at such a
如果我们看这样一个超级复杂
mapping this is like the canonical
映射这就像规范
example more or less we have this free
例如或多或少，我们有这个免费的
entity some you would like to purchase
您想购买的实体
them into the database using JP a and
使用JP a将它们输入数据库
hibernate so the things first things
冬眠，所以事情首先
that we do we put these annotations like
我们把这些注释像
an entity the ID one-to-many an order
实体ID一对多订单
has multiple order items an order item
有多个订单商品
relates to a product so this is already
与某个产品有关，所以这已经是
bad because the order is a reserved
不好，因为订单是保留订单
keyword so we have to put at the table
关键字，所以我们必须摆在桌子上
but this is actually not a really big
但这实际上不是很大
deal but I had to run it first actually
交易，但实际上我必须先运行它
to find it out so then we write the code
找到它，然后我们编写代码
with most likely spring data JPA that
与最有可能的 spring data JPA
looks more or less like this and we
看起来或多或少像这样，我们
expect it to work flawlessly but what
期望它可以完美地工作，但是
actually happens is that we get this
实际上发生的是，我们得到了这个
exception to transient object exception
临时对象异常的例外
that the object references the unsafe
该对象引用了不安全的对象
transient instance and for someone who
临时实例，并为某人
is let's say at the junior level this is
假设在初级阶段，这是
very kind of cryptic message like what
像这样的隐秘信息
what does it mean of course I mean you
这当然是什么意思
have to learn JPA to really understand
必须学习JPA才能真正理解
it but you have to put the Cascade type
它，但您必须输入Cascade类型
all and then the code works well except
全部，然后代码运行良好，除了
the database structure that it creates
它创建的数据库结构
is not something that I would least
我至少不会
expect because between the order and
期望，因为订单和
order item we have a one to many
订购项目我们有一对多
relations but the database structure
关系但数据库结构
that is generated or the what hibernate
生成或什么冬眠
expects is different so what we how we
期望是不同的，所以我们如何
can fix it we have to put another
可以解决它，我们必须放另一个
annotation that is a joint column and
作为联合列的注释，以及
then we will get the database structure
然后我们将获得数据库结构
that we actually
我们实际上
we expect and there are many people's
我们期望，有很多人
that struggle with these kind of
与这类斗争
problems
问题
and every time you have this kind of
每次你有这种
problem you have to run the application
您必须运行应用程序的问题
to run the test to see how it actually
运行测试以查看其实际效果
works and this is just a simple example
有效，这只是一个简单的例子
you could go actually much deeper with
你实际上可以更深入
all these little things in hibernate
所有这些小事情都在休眠
that make a big difference so how do
那有很大的不同，那怎么办
most of the people usually handle this
大多数人通常会处理这个
issue they go to that blog and that is a
问题，他们去那个博客，那是一个
huge to work as a hibernate sorry yes
像冬眠般工作很抱歉
hibernate developer advocate and he's
冬眠的开发者拥护者，他是
basically the guy who knows everything
基本上谁都知道的家伙
about the hibernate so he everyone goes
关于冬眠，所以他每个人都去
to his blog post and it's it's not a big
到他的博客文章，这不是很大
surprise that he has hundreds of
惊讶的是他有数百个
thousands of visitors per month because
每月有成千上万的访客，因为
his content is actually very very good
他的内容实际上非常非常好
and he addresses the real problems
他解决了真正的问题
people have and I'm not even saying only
人们有，我什至不只说
that a junior developers problem like
像是初级开发者的问题
normal people who work in the business
从事业务的普通人
for years have this issues including me
多年来有这个问题，包括我
because I tend to forget this kind of
因为我倾向于忘记这种
stuff so he basically explains
东西，所以他基本上解释
everything like how you should do things
像你应该怎么做的一切
with hibernate how to make this works
与冬眠如何使这项工作
like good from the perform performance
表现出色
point of view and I was like wondering
的观点，我想知道
it would be actually nice something to
这实际上是一件很棒的事情
have something like that as a service
有这样的服务
this would be the best so that I then I
这将是最好的，这样我就可以
actually don't have to go to his block
其实不必去他的街区
whenever I find an issue that just
每当我发现一个问题
somehow works for me and there that
以某种方式为我工作，那里
developed recently a tool called hyper
最近开发了一种名为hyper的工具
persistence optimizer
持久性优化器
which is not free but it's also
这不是免费的，但它也是
inexpensive and I think especially if
便宜，我想特别是如果
you work in a bigger company that has a
您在一家规模较大的公司工作，
bigger budget this is a tool that is
更大的预算，这是一个工具
maybe worth considering so hyper nice
也许值得考虑
hyper persistence optimizer is a tool
超持久性优化器是一个工具
that meant to work like as flat as a
意味着像
service so basically you have your code
服务，所以基本上你有你的代码
you ask that and it tells you what is
你问那个，它告诉你什么是
wrong and the usage of it is very simple
错误，它的用法很简单
so you add just one dependency to your
所以你只添加一个依赖
project I think it's still in the snap
我认为该项目仍在紧要关头
snapshot I don't know and you put this
快照我不知道，你把这个
test class this test class I didn't even
我什至没有参加这个测试班
go deep what is actually doing it just
深入了解实际在做什么
copy-paste it from like the guide how
像指南一样复制粘贴
you should use it and it introspects all
您应该使用它，它可以内省所有
your mappings
您的映射
and JDBC configurations and as an output
和JDBC配置，并作为输出
you get something like that so this is
你得到类似的东西，所以这是
what I run this code against my some of
我针对我的一些代码运行此代码
my classes so it immediately gives you
我的课，所以它立即给你
the hints what did you mess up in your
提示你把自己弄得一团糟
hibernate configuration some of them you
休眠配置其中一些你
can maybe agree in my case they were
可以同意我的情况
both critical that was kind of a
两者都很关键
surprise but yes so this is something
惊喜，但是是的，这就是
definitely worth considering at least
绝对值得至少考虑
there is a trial version so you can
有一个试用版，所以你可以
always try it out but if we go back to
总是尝试一下，但是如果我们回到
the to this design to these entities
这些实体的设计
that we have that let's say now are
我们现在说的是
correct according to JPA and hibernate
根据JPA正确设置并休眠
there are still lots of questions that
仍然有很多问题
remain unanswered
仍然没有答案
so which entity should have
所以哪个实体应该有
corresponding repository should order
相应的存储库应订购
item have a reference to product and
项目有产品参考
should order item have a reference to
订单商品应参考
order I mean there are multiple ways how
我的意思是有多种方式
you can structure it with JPA and
您可以使用JPA和
hibernate and it doesn't really tell you
冬眠，它并没有真正告诉你
how to do it right it leaves you it
如何正确做就离开了
leaves it up to you and most of these
由您自己决定，其中大多数
questions were already answered in this
问题已经在此得到解答
book or in general by domain driven
书或一般由域驱动
design they tell you how to structure
设计，他们告诉你如何构造
the project and with this knowledge
该项目并以此知识
probably you can go quite far and this
也许你可以走很远，这
is how we transition to the to the
是我们过渡到的方式
spring data project in general so spring
spring data 项目总体上如此春季
data is a is a project that it's built
数据是它建立的一个项目
with domain driven design in mind so
考虑到域驱动设计
obviously you have the repositories you
显然，您拥有存储库
have your entities I think everyone
有你的实体，我想每个人
knows more or less how it works because
或多或少知道它是如何工作的，因为
it has become a standard and I was
它已经成为一种标准，我当时
looking like what is the the oldest note
看起来是最古老的音符
about spring data project and I couldn't
关于 spring data 项目，我不能
find anything about the like the version
找到任何关于喜欢的版本
but let's say one put I mean there was a
但是，假设我说的是一个
blog post about 1.0 but actually the
关于1.0的博客文章，但实际上
spring data JPA has grown out of the
JPA的 spring data 已经超出了
project called hadas developed by oliver
奥利弗开发的名为hadas的项目
dropped born something like that I hope
希望我能出生
I didn't miss it
我没有错过
and the hardest was was like the the
最难的是
project before before the spring date a
春季日期之前的项目
JPA and it was in based on the idea
JPA正是基于这个想法
provided by a bear heart valve in the in
由熊心瓣膜在
the magazine in the in the article and
文章中的杂志和
this later on it transitioned into into
后来它变成了
spring data JPA and spring data in
Spring 数据JPA和中的Spring 数据
general I find it very fascinating that
总的来说，我感到非常着迷
the library that basically changed
基本上改变了的图书馆
everything related to relational
与关系有关的一切
persistence how we write applications
坚持我们编写应用程序的方式
and basically how our applications also
以及基本上我们的应用程序
affect the world has is a result of the
影响世界的原因是
article written and that could be also a
撰写的文章，也可能是
blog post so if you have some ideas I
博客文章，所以，如果您有一些想法，我
would strongly encourage to write a blog
强烈鼓励写博客
post because you never know how it may
发布，因为你永远不知道这可能
end up and the one feature about the
最后，关于
spring data that I would like to speak
我想说的 spring data
about is something that is not very well
关于不是很好
known and I think it's a little bit
众所周知，我认为这有点
under use because there are many nice
正在使用，因为有很多不错的
use cases for it and this is about
用例，这是关于
publishing domain events from aggregates
从聚合发布域事件
roots let's consider the following code
根源，让我们考虑以下代码
we have an order and the order can be
我们有一个订单，该订单可以是
confirmed so this is like the very
确定，所以这就像
typical business method for confirming
确认的典型业务方法
the order this is how usually it starts
这是通常开始的顺序
but later on we've got another
但是后来我们有了另一个
requirement that whenever order is
要求每当有订单
confirmed we have to notify the customer
确认我们必须通知客户
that the no order was confirmed then
然后确认没有订单
later on it goes another thing that you
后来又发生了另一件事，你
know maybe push notifications have to be
知道推送通知可能是
sent and and so on so basically this
发送等等，基本上这样
method is a perfect candidate for ever
方法永远是一个完美的候选人
growing method and we at some point may
生长方法，我们在某个时候可能
start to lose what is the actual domain
开始失去实际的领域
logic here and what are just the
这里的逻辑是什么
separate different concerns and there is
分开不同的问题，有
a way to address it with spring we can
用 Spring 解决这个问题的方法
use the spring built in event bus so we
使用内置事件总线的spring，所以我们
can inject the application even
甚至可以注入应用程序
publisher and then whenever this thing
发布者，然后每当这件事
happens we just publish a new event that
发生了，我们只是发布了一个新事件
the order is confirmed and the order
订单已确认，订单
confirmed is just a very simple class
确定只是一个非常简单的类
with whatever fields
与任何领域
we meet in this case it's just an ID and
在这种情况下，我们见面只是一个ID，
then we have decouple this whole sending
那么我们已经将整个发送过程解耦了
email pushing notifications and whatever
电子邮件推送通知等
other concerns are there in two separate
其他问题分为两个部分
components that just listen for these
只听这些的组件
events this is already looking good but
事件，这已经看起来不错，但
spring data gives us options to make it
spring data 使我们可以选择
even better so instead of publishing
甚至更好，而不是发布
this event in the in the in the method
方法中的
itself we can make an order as an A+
本身，我们可以作为A +订购
that extends abstract aggregate route
扩展了抽象的聚合路线
and abstract aggregate root gives us an
抽象的聚合根为我们提供了
option to register event so whenever
选择注册事件，以便每当
something happens inside the aggregate
骨料内部发生了一些事情
we can register event that something
我们可以注册事件
like this happened so everything stays
这样的事情发生了，所以一切都保持不变
like changing the changing the state
就像改变状态一样
including publishing the events it
包括发布事件
states inside the aggregate and what
聚合内的状态以及什么
happens then instead of having this even
然后发生，而不是有这个甚至
publisher published event we can just
发布者发布的事件，我们可以
save the method and spring data under
将方法和Spring 数据保存在
the hood whenever the aggregate is saved
只要保存了骨料，就可以罩住
it emits all the events that were
它发出所有的事件
registered before so we basically ended
注册之前，所以我们基本上结束了
up with a method that looks exactly like
看起来很像的方法
like the beginning with all these nice
就像所有这些美好的开始
features and in my opinion this looks
功能，我认为这看起来
really good and the separation of
真的很好，分离
concerns is something that it's worth
关注是值得的
looking at so let's look at the another
看着，让我们看看另一个
example it's a little bit trivialized
例如，它有点琐碎
but it's just to get to the point so
但这只是为了切题
this is a very typical use case when
这是一个非常典型的用例
you're working with relational databases
您正在使用关系数据库
that we not just have a crud where we
我们不只是在哪里
fetch the data save the data and so on
提取数据保存数据，依此类推
but we have to perform some either
但是我们要么执行一些
aggregations or reporting for example to
汇总或报告，例如
build such a nice HTML table and the end
建立如此漂亮的HTML表格，最后
and a very naive to wait to do it with
非常天真地等待着与
hibernate and JPA is to just like have a
休眠和JPA就像拥有一个
Mike you have an order so why not just
迈克，你有订单，那为什么不
to have a method that returns these
有一个返回这些的方法
quantities since all the order items are
数量，因为所有订单项均为
already there this method looks
已经有这种方法了
perfectly fine from the object-oriented
来自面向对象的完美
point of view so if you write something
观点，所以如果你写点东西
like this in your object-oriented
这样在您的面向对象
classes and university
班级和大学
probably you would pass but what happens
也许你会过去，但是会发生什么
under the hood is a little bit scary so
引擎盖下有点吓人
then if we execute something like this I
那如果我们执行这样的事情
mean one query is to fetch the order and
意思是一个查询是要获取订单，
then for each order item there is a
然后每个订单项都有一个
executed separate query under the hood
在后台执行单独的查询
while if we would do it with just with a
而如果我们只用一个
sequel it will be as simple as that
续集就这么简单
that's like the sequel 101 so the lesson
就像续集101这样的课程
that comes from it is that hibernated &amp;
来自它的是冬眠的＆
JP is a not alternative to sequel
JP不能代替续集
whenever you use hibernate and j.j PA
每当您使用休眠和jj PA
which are great tools don't forget that
那些很棒的工具不要忘记
sequel is still the tool that you could
续集仍然是您可以使用的工具
use and probably should use but then the
使用，可能应该使用，但随后
question is how do we execute native
问题是我们如何执行本机
sequel when we use die JPA in hibernate
在休眠状态下使用die JPA的续集
and one of the ways to do it is to put
而做到这一点的方法之一就是
something like this on the under entity
在下面的实体上这样的东西
like to create a named and native query
喜欢创建一个命名的本地查询
and I think this is something like a
我认为这有点像
sane person or not sign like I mean the
理智的人或不签名，我的意思是
average person like me cannot really
像我这样的普通人真的不能
memorize like so I would have to google
像这样记住，我将不得不谷歌
it all the time like I mean this
一直像我的意思
annotation tree is not very tempting at
注释树不是很诱人
least but fortunately we have spring
至少但幸运的是我们有 Spring
data so we can do it in a much much
数据，所以我们可以做很多事情
nicer way right so every spring data
更好的方法，所以每个 Spring 的数据
method we know all know that we can
我们都知道的方法我们知道
spring that at JPA I mean we know that
Spring ，在JPA，我的意思是我们知道
we can put the query annotation where we
我们可以将查询注释放在
can write the J pql query but there's
可以编写J pql查询，但是有
also this one property native query true
也是这一属性本机查询true
that lets us execute native sequel and
让我们执行本地续集，
this looks already much better and this
这看起来已经好多了，这
is like I believe the default way to
就像我相信默认的方式
actually executing simple queries when
实际上在执行简单查询时
you use spring data JPA the problem
您使用spring data JPA的问题
really starts when we have to build
真正开始，当我们必须建立
something more sophisticated and when we
更复杂的东西，当我们
have a let's say we build a search
假设我们建立了搜寻
engine and we have multiple criteria to
引擎，我们有多个条件
choose from and this is the the property
选择，这是财产
search in Spain called photo castle you
在西班牙搜寻被称为相片城堡的人
can like choose different prices
可以选择不同的价格
different criteria or how you want to
不同的标准或您想要的方式
pick your flat and
选择你的公寓
like building it with sequel is also
就像用续集构建它一样
quite challenging so I took Hill only
很有挑战性，所以我只带了希尔
the subset of the price so here we want
价格的子集，所以我们要在这里
to like select the the flats that fit
喜欢选择适合的公寓
into particular price part of this code
转换为该代码的特定价格部分
is almost delegated so at the beginning
几乎被委派了，所以一开始
we have to build a sequel query at the
我们必须在处建立一个续集查询
end we have to set the parameters to not
最后，我们必须将参数设置为
have any simple injections and this code
有任何简单的注射和此代码
is very very error-prone because when we
非常容易出错，因为当我们
build the sequel queries manually it
手动建立续集查询
means that we are vulnerable to any type
意味着我们容易受到任何类型的伤害
of like silly mistakes so we can forget
像愚蠢的错误，所以我们可以忘记
the comma we can put the space or we can
逗号，我们可以放空格或者我们可以
forget the space we can put extra comma
忘记我们可以加逗号的空格
basically like string concatenation is
基本上像字符串连接是
not the greatest way to build sequel
不是制作续集的最好方法
queries and this is whether we come to
查询，这就是我们是否来
the tool that it's called joke yes so
是个玩笑的工具
joke is not not not a new framework but
笑话不是一个新的框架，而是
also it's not as popular as as hibernate
也不像冬眠那么流行
jook jook is a tool developed by Lukas
jook jook是Lukas开发的工具
adder and Lukas adder is like the most
加法器和Lukas加法器最像
popular and I maybe even the most
受欢迎，我什至最
knowledgeable person like on the edge of
有知识的人喜欢在边缘
Java and sequel in the world so
Java和续集如此
basically he developed this to himself
基本上，他自己开发了这个
and it seems like he knows everything
好像他什么都知道
about sequel and he developed a tool
关于续集，他开发了一种工具
called joke and the joke it's like the
叫做笑话，这个笑话就像
mission statement is quite clear it
任务说明很清楚
generates the Java code from the
从生成Java代码
database to build fluent compile time
数据库建立流畅的编译时间
friendly let's say sequel queries thing
友好的说，续集查询的东西
to note is that drug is not an ORM so
要注意的是，药物不是ORM，因此
it's not meant to compete with JPA or
这并不意味着要与JPA竞争，或者
hibernate it's also not a spring data
休眠它也不是spring数据
project it is just a library to build
项目它只是一个要构建的库
typesafe sequel queries and it's
类型安全续集查询，它是
fantastic when you have to build complex
当您必须建造复杂建筑时，这太棒了
queries to database so it's fantastic
查询数据库，这太棒了
for reading the data it may not be that
读取数据可能不是
great if you if you want to save the
很棒，如果您想保存
data so of course there is a possibility
数据，所以当然有可能
to save the data
保存数据
from my experience working with our ms
根据我与我们女士合作的经验
when you have to like fetch the data
当您需要获取数据时
change it modify the state and persist
更改它，修改状态并保持不变
it is often much easier with just JPA or
只需JPA或
hibernate and Juke works in a way that
冬眠和乔克的工作方式
it puts a little bit more effort on the
它在
on the build time so when you build your
在构建时间上，所以当您构建自己的
project it introspects the database and
进行项目内省数据库
then generate Java classes for you and
然后为您生成Java类，并
these Java classes reflect exactly what
这些Java类完全反映了
you have in the database so that later
您已经在数据库中，以便以后
on when you build a query you can just
建立查询时，您可以
use it just like importing normal Java
就像导入普通Java一样使用它
classes and the benefit is that whenever
上课的好处是
your database structure changes and it
您的数据库结构发生了变化
changes in a way that is incorrect to
以不正确的方式改变
the metals you implemented you will it
您实施的金属，您会的
will fail during the compilation time if
如果在编译期间失败，则
we look at this the simplest one sequel
我们看这个最简单的续集
query this is how it looks like when you
查询这是当您时的样子
use Juke so it comes with a DSL that
使用Juke，因此它带有DSL，
looks very familiar for SQL developers
对于SQL开发人员来说看起来很熟悉
as well as Java developers all this
以及Java开发人员
order item and order ID this is all from
订单商品和订单ID都来自
the from these generated classes but
这些生成的类中的
it's always easy on trivial examples
在简单的例子上总是很容易
let's see how it looks like on this more
让我们再看看它的样子
complex one so we are back to the
复杂的一个，所以我们回到
searching for the for the properties
搜索属性
this is the way when we concatenate
这是我们串联的方式
strings manually this is the how we do
手动字符串这是我们的工作方式
it with joke the the the Select part is
开玩笑吧，选择部分是
here at the bottom like will we select
在底部，就像我们会选择
we can specify the conditions but first
我们可以指定条件，但首先
it gives us type safety but also we do
它为我们提供了类型安全性，但我们也做到了
it all at once so instead of splitting
这一切都是一次的，而不是分裂
like before that first we have to build
像在那之前，我们必须建立
a query then we have to bind the
一个查询，然后我们必须绑定
parameters instead with joke whenever we
每当我们改变参数时
specify the query we set already what
指定我们已经设置的查询
are the values and Duke under the hood
是价值观和引擎盖下的公爵
does all that we expect to happen if you
如果您愿意，我们会做的一切
would like to start with joke it's of
想从开玩笑开始
course like the first thing to do is to
当然，要做的第一件事就是
go to its main page George long recorded
转到其主页乔治长期以来记录在案
a couple of videos in the spring tips
Spring 的一些视频提示
serious about the joke and there is also
认真讲笑话，还有
one fantastic review presentation from
一位出色的评论演讲者
Michael Simmons
迈克尔·西蒙斯
from spring aiyo 2017 where he where he
从2017年春季aiyo开始
shows how it looks like how they use it
展示他们如何使用它
in in their project and joke is really
在他们的项目中，笑话真的
well integrated with spring boot so you
与 spring boot 很好地集成在一起，因此您
can also choose the joke starter on the
也可以在
start dot spring IO page so we talked
开始点Spring IO页面，所以我们谈到了
about the the JPA that is a Java centric
关于以Java为中心的JPA
and the joke that a sequel centric now
还有一个以续集为中心的笑话
there will be something in the middle so
中间会有东西，所以
there's a new framework from spring data
spring data 有了一个新的框架
spring data JDBC and it's the first
Spring数据JDBC，这是第一个
version 1.0 was released October last
1.0版本于去年10月发布
year and it started with this idea that
年，从这个想法开始
people want to interact with relational
人们想与关系互动
databases but they don't want to use JPA
数据库，但他们不想使用JPA
because maybe because that's already my
因为也许因为那已经是我的
assumption because of the JPA complexity
由于JPA的复杂性而做出的假设
and because of all the features that the
并且由于所有功能
APA has that maybe people don't
APA可能人们没有
necessarily need so the spring data JDBC
必然需要这样的Spring数据JDBC
is comes with a simple ORM and it
带有一个简单的ORM，它
embraces domain driven design it's built
包含其构建的域驱动设计
from the ground up so there is no JPA
从头开始，所以没有JPA
you will not it doesn't implement JPA
您不会，它不会实现JPA
there is no hibernate under the hood of
没有冬眠的引擎盖下
course what we find out under the hood
当然我们在幕后发现了什么
is the JDBC and it since it's a spring
是JDBC，因为它是 Spring
data project it follows the same
数据项目也一样
principle so there is a repository there
原理，所以那里有一个仓库
are mapping classes and there are also
是映射类，还有
templates and if you use it it feels
模板，如果您使用它，感觉
actually at least for me it feels more
实际上至少对我而言
like interacting with maybe MongoDB like
喜欢与MongoDB进行交互
the that's like the same level of
就像在同一水平
simplicity that I found in spring data
我在 spring data 中发现的简单性
MongoDB is the same with spring data
Spring数据与MongoDB相同
JDBC it's just very very predictable it
JDBC是非常非常可预测的
has been developed mainly by Jen's
主要由Jen's开发
shoulder from the spring data team and
由 spring data 团队负责
now let's have a look how the example
现在让我们看一下示例
that I showed before with JPA would look
我之前在JPA上展示过的
like with spring data JDBC on the left
就像左边的spring数据JDBC
hand side we have the same we have the
手侧，我们拥有相同的
same code that we've seen before on the
与我们之前在
right hand side it's the same but mapped
右侧相同，但已映射
with spring data JDBC so the first thing
使用Spring数据JDBC，所以第一件事
to note is that uses difference
要注意的是，使用差异
of annotations as there are much fewer
注释的数量少得多
of them so the ID that you see on the
其中的一个，因此您在
right-hand side is not the same ID as
右侧的ID与
from Java X persistence it also drives
从Java X持久性也可以驱动
your design so if you look closer the
您的设计，所以如果您仔细看
order item does not refer to the product
订单商品与产品无关
entity anymore I mean it does refer but
实体了，我的意思是它确实引用了
only by ID not really by the by the type
仅按ID而不按类型
as it is in the JPA and this is because
就像在JPA中一样，这是因为
order an order item this is a different
订购订单商品这是不同的
aggregate than product product they are
比产品产品总和
according like to domain-driven design
根据领域驱动设计
these are two separate aggregates and
这是两个单独的集合
according to domain driven design
根据域驱动设计
aggregate should not reference each
聚合不应引用每个
other by the type but rather by ID and
其他按类型而是ID和
since spring data's JDBC embraces domain
因为spring数据的JDBC包含域
driven design is just not possible to do
驱动设计是不可能做到的
it with a product if you would put
它与产品，如果你愿意
product over here you would get like
产品在这里你会喜欢
totally unexpected results and it
完全出乎意料的结果
wouldn't make any sense at all and now
现在完全没有任何意义
you may say that you could do the same
你可能会说你可以做同样的事情
with JPA right so nothing stop us stops
使用JPA正确，所以没有什么可以阻止我们停止
us from using a product ID over here on
我们从这里开始使用产品ID
the JPA side and this is true but the
JPA方面，这是事实，但
problem with with JPA is that it doesn't
JPA的问题是它不会
enforce it so even if you come up with a
强制执行，即使您提出了
very nice design you structure your
非常好的设计，您可以构建自己的
entities according to all the domain
所有领域的实体
driven design recommendations it's still
驱动的设计建议仍然
it's very likely that at one point
在某一点上很有可能
someone new comes to the project that
有人来了这个项目
doesn't understand these design
不理解这些设计
constraints maybe you will leave the
约束，也许你会离开
project and the whole architecture
项目和整个架构
around how the entities are structure is
关于实体的结构是
gone and you end up again in a mess the
走了，你又陷入了混乱
database schema that is expected for
预期的数据库架构
this kind of mapping is like
这种映射就像
automatically reasonable so springdale
自动合理，所以斯普林代尔
JDBC is also quite opinionated about the
JDBC也对
schema this is exactly what it you can
模式，这正是您可以做到的
change the column names like do the vary
更改列名称，例如进行更改
basic stuff but it's not the framework
基本的东西，但不是框架
that it's meant to cover whatever
它的意思是涵盖任何
database structure you have it's rather
你拥有的数据库结构
this is how we do it this is how we
这就是我们的方法这就是我们的方法
should do it so if you're working with a
应该这样做，如果您正在使用
Legacy Project and you would like to
旧版项目，您想
start using JDBC a spring data JDBC for
开始使用JDBC的Spring数据JDBC
this project this may not end up well
这个项目可能不会很好地结束
but if you are starting something new
但是如果您开始新的东西
that's probably something you may
那可能是你可能会发生的事
consider how to use it I mean the usage
考虑如何使用它，我的意思是用法
is very very similar so you also have a
非常相似，所以您也有一个
repositories when you need another to
需要其他存储库时
add a new method you just add a new
添加新方法您只需添加新方法
method with a couple of exceptions so
方法有几个例外，所以
one thing is that spring data JDBC goes
一件事是spring数据JDBC去了
at least until now or at least at least
至少直到现在或至少
one one oh my soul free because
一一哦，我的灵魂自由，因为
yesterday was my son for release that I
昨天是我儿子要释放，我
didn't check it implements the crud
没有检查它是否实现了目标
repository meaning you get all the like
仓库意味着你得到所有类似的东西
the basic fine save delete methods but
基本的精细保存删除方法，但是
it doesn't implement paging and sorting
它没有实现分页和排序
repository so pagination is not let's
存储库，所以不要让分页
say trivial as it is with others bring
说平淡无奇
data projects also it doesn't support
也不支持的数据项目
derived queries derived query is a query
派生查询派生查询是一个查询
that you don't have to write but it's
你不必写，但这是
rather like derived from the method name
就像从方法名派生
so with the spring data JPA this method
所以用Spring 数据JPA这种方法
would work perfectly fine fine by status
按状态可以很好地工作
in case of spring data JDBC we have to
如果是Spring数据JDBC，我们必须
explicitly write what is the sequel
明确写出什么是续集
query we expect to be it to be executed
查询我们希望它会被执行
I don't actually think that is this is a
我实际上不认为这是一个
big deal maybe it's even better it makes
大不了，也许更好
things more explicit and of course it
事情更加明确，当然
works with the traditional spring
与传统的 Spring 一起工作
transaction management
交易管理
there is only one thing that is
只有一件事是
different if this code would be written
如果编写此代码则不同
with spring data JPA I mean this
与 spring data JPA，我的意思是
confirmed method the safe method will
确认方法安全方法
not be really needed right because
并不需要，因为
whenever we find we load an entity from
每当我们发现从
the from the repository this is a
从存储库中，这是一个
managed entity by JP a so JP a and
由JP a管理的实体，因此JP a和
hibernate they track the changes that
冬眠，他们跟踪的变化
happen in the state and whatever the
发生在该州以及任何
methods is over the transactions over
方法已经结束了
the changes are flushed to the database
更改将刷新到数据库
in case of spring data JDBC it's aimed
对于spring数据JDBC，它的目标是
to be transparent simple so it will not
要透明简单，所以不会
do stuff that you don't expect it to do
做您不希望做的事情
if you don't execute the safe method the
如果您不执行安全方法，
saving will not happen this is this
保存不会发生，这是这个
point what I feel like it's more closer
指出我感觉更接近
to spring data MongoDB then then
产生数据MongoDB然后
actually to the JPA which is again it's
实际上是JPA，这又是
not good or bad it's just a feature to
不管是好是坏
consider and I personally like it a lot
考虑，我个人非常喜欢
it also implements all the all the
它也实现了所有
goodies about the domain events that are
关于域事件的好东西是
mentioned before sometimes the question
之前提到过的问题
is what is missing there are quite a lot
缺少的是很多
of things missing if you want to compare
如果要比较，缺少的东西
it with hibernate so there's no dirty
它与冬眠，所以没有脏
tracking no lazy loading and this is
跟踪没有延迟加载，这是
actually by design
实际上是设计使然
there is no caching so there is no
没有缓存，所以没有
session cuz there's there's no second
会议，因为没有第二个
level cache if you want to do caching
一级缓存，如果您想进行缓存
you have to use the spring application
您必须使用spring应用程序
level caching which again is not
级别缓存又不是
actually bad right it's it's maybe it's
其实很糟糕，也许是
maybe it's even better and there are no
也许更好，没有
many-to-one and many-to-many relations
多对一和多对多关系
because they just don't fit into domain
因为他们只是不适合领域
driven design concepts but what you get
驱动的设计概念，但您会得到什么
instead is it's simple predictable
相反，这很容易预测
embraces sequel and enforces good design
拥抱续集并保持良好的设计
and these are good enough reasons to at
这些都是足够好的理由
least consider it
至少考虑一下
what is like a side effect of it that
它的副作用是什么
since entities since aggregate can
因为实体可以聚合
reference each other only by ID it means
仅通过ID互相引用
that also it's nothing stops you from
那也没什么能阻止你
storing different aggregates and
存储不同的聚合
different data sources it often may make
经常可能产生的不同数据源
sense to store part of your application
存储部分应用程序的感觉
in the relational database but the other
在关系数据库中，但另一个
part for example in Redis when you
一部分，例如在Redis中，当您
reference the entity is only through IDs
仅通过ID引用实体
then you have this flexibility and we
那么您就拥有了这种灵活性，我们
spoke right now about these three
现在就谈到这三个
frameworks and they have all of them
框架，它们都有
have two things or one thing in common
有两个或一个共同点
they are all based on JDBC and they are
它们都是基于JDBC的
all blocking which is not necessarily an
所有阻止，不一定是
issue but it's just a fact we now are in
问题，但这只是我们现在所处的事实
the stage where we talk a lot about
我们谈论很多的阶段
reactive reactive frameworks Sprintweb
反应式反应框架Sprintweb
flux and of course the blocking
通量，当然还有阻塞
connection on the JDBC level does not
JDBC级别的连接不正确
fit very well we can over we can work
非常合适，我们可以胜任工作
around that with having tread pools but
周围有踏板池，但是
still I mean we so we used a reactive to
我仍然是说我们如此反应
avoid having use you know using multiple
避免让您知道使用多个
threads and then we end up with a thread
线程，然后我们得到一个线程
pool doesn't fit very well and this is
游泳池不太适合，这是
where we come to the point where what
我们到了什么地方
are 2d BC comps and Ben Hale already
是2d BC comps和Ben Hale
said most of the stuff I wanted to say
说了我想说的大部分内容
at the keynote and he also gives a talk
在主题演讲中，他还发表了演讲
today at 5:00 that I would strongly
今天在5:00，我会坚决
encourage you to come if you are a
鼓励你来，如果你是一个
little bit in this topic but what is our
这个话题有点，但是我们的是什么
2d BC art ODBC is the is the is the spec
2d BC art ODBC是规范
and also a library that lives more or
还有一个寿命更长的图书馆
less on the same level as JDBC but just
少了与JDBC相同的级别，只是
for the reactive let's say site of
对于反应性，我们说
spring or not only spring because it's
Spring 还是不仅因为 Spring
not bound to spring in in any way and
不以任何方式反弹
this gives us I mean other than
这给我们我的意思是
reactivity the for me the very important
反应性对我来说很重要
point is that there is just non blocking
关键是没有阻塞
so whenever we fetch the data from the
因此，每当我们从
database instead of getting the data
数据库而不是获取数据
immediately we get this mono or flux and
立即我们得到这个单声道或助焊剂，
our 2d BC is split into multiple types
我们的2d BC分为多种类型
of api's unlike JDBC so they basically
api与JDBC不同，因此它们基本上
took the lessons learned from JDBC that
从JDBC中吸取的教训
maybe JDBC API is not necessarily like
也许JDBC API不一定像
the API you would like to use in your
您想在自己的API中使用的API
project but maybe it's good for the
项目，但也许对
library providers right so maybe you
图书馆提供者，所以也许你
want this low-level stuff if you build a
如果您构建了一个
framework on the top of JDBC are 2 DB C
JDBC顶部的框架是2 DB C
so if R 2 DB C we have this spi that
所以如果R 2 DB C我们有这个spi
it's meant to be used by framework
它应该由框架使用
provider
提供者
like if you want to build a framework on
就像您想建立一个框架
the top of our 2d BC you get this
我们2d BC的顶部
low-level stuff that I personally like
我个人喜欢的低级内容
again I wouldn't like to see it in my in
再次，我不想在我的家中看到它
my production code base right but having
我的生产代码基本正确，但是有
this flow level components and functions
此流量级别的组件和功能
makes a lot of sense when you want to
当你想要的时候很有意义
build the next RM on the top of our 2d
在2d的顶部建立下一个RM
BC they also come with with our 2d BC
公元前，他们还附带了我们的二维公元前
client that already took stakes is one
已经赌注的客户是一个
level up so now let's say if you want to
升级，现在让我们说如果你想
execute something in transaction you can
可以执行一些交易
use RTD BC in transaction and the call
在交易和通话中使用RTD BC
feels much more natural to to normal
感觉比正常人自然得多
application developers and there are of
应用程序开发人员
course also other frameworks that are
当然还有其他框架
built on the top of it
建立在它的顶部
one is spring data r2 DBC which again
一个是Spring 数据r2 DBC
like elevates at one level apps to make
例如将应用程序提升一级
this code even nicer and also something
该代码甚至更好，也有一些
that we are totally used to meaning you
我们完全习惯了你的意思
can build a build a repository extend
可以建立一个构建库扩展
the reactive code repository and have
反应性代码存储库并具有
the same stuff as you would normally
和平时一样的东西
expect this is this is alpha stage so
期望这是Alpha阶段，所以
it's I think it's not yet recommended to
我认为它不建议
use in production but I mean who never
用于生产中，但我的意思是谁从来没有
used alpha stage projects I know five
我知道使用过的Alpha阶段项目五个
minutes okay I'm faster okay and just
分钟好吧，我更快，好
come to Ben Hale stock it's at five and
来本·黑尔股票，五点钟
the one the last thing that I would like
那是我想要的最后一件事
to talk is and how can we test it so the
要说的是，我们如何测试它，所以
historically we had a lots of issues
历史上我们有很多问题
with writing integration tests for
通过编写集成测试
relational databases code right so we
关系数据库代码正确，所以我们
use this in memory databases as a
在内存数据库中将其用作
replacement and it kind of works but
更换和它的作品，但
it's never the same like we use some of
就像我们使用一些
the some of the abilities of the real
真正的一些能力
databases so you either don't use them
数据库，所以您要么不使用它们
or you just don't test them and there's
或者你只是不测试它们，
a framework that that helps us to
一个可以帮助我们
actually test the databases the database
实际测试数据库
related code properly and this framework
正确的相关代码和这个框架
is called test containers it's not only
被称为测试容器
for testing database is in general used
一般用于测试数据库
to spin up whatever docker container you
旋转您所使用的任何Docker容器
want from your java code and I will show
想要从您的Java代码开始，我将展示
only subset of it of how to use it with
关于如何使用它的唯一子集
relational databases so you add a
关系数据库，因此您添加了一个
dependency to test containers in my case
在我的情况下对测试容器的依赖
it's Postgres then you just put a
这是Postgres，然后您只需输入一个
different properties to to your spring
Spring 的特性不同
boot configuration and this part is
引导配置，这部分是
especially in
特别是在
Orton that you prefix this JDBC TC
您为该JDBC TC加上前缀的Orton
PostgreSQL and it works in a way that
PostgreSQL，它的工作方式
when application starts the container
当应用程序启动容器时
database driver pulls the docker image
数据库驱动程序提取docker映像
started under the hood and your
开始在引擎盖下
application is free to use the real
应用程序可以免费使用真实
database like I mean almost
像我的意思是数据库
transparently right so then you can just
透明地正确，这样您就可以
write a normal code like the code that
像这样写一个普通的代码
you are used to you also have to opt out
你习惯了，你也不得不选择退出
for replacing the test database with
用替换测试数据库
with the spring test support so the key
与Spring 测试的支持，所以关键
takeaways from this talk that I would
我想从这次演讲中总结
like you to remember there was this
像你一样记得
there is a world beyond the JPA and
JPA之外还有一个世界
there is nothing also wrong about the JP
JP也没有错
JP is a fantastic framework it's I mean
JP是一个很棒的框架，我的意思是
there's the most feature-rich framework
有功能最丰富的框架
I think on the planet to interact with
我认为在地球上可以互动
the to do object relational mapping but
做对象关系映射，但是
it's it's not a silver bullet there are
这不是银弹
other options as well embrace the sequel
其他选项也包括续集
whenever you need to do something more
每当你需要做更多的事情
complex with the database I mean you use
与数据库复杂，我的意思是您使用
the sequel databases it's silly to not
续集数据库很愚蠢
use the power of it consider spring data
利用它的力量考虑Spring 数据
JDBC to your to your project it's still
JDBC到您的项目中
early stage it's still a little bit
初期还有点
buggy the version 1.1 is much more
越野车1.1版的功能更多
promising it's actually that's the
承诺实际上就是
version that I like to use but it's
我喜欢使用的版本，但是
still in the milestone for right now but
目前仍处于里程碑
if you are going to like build a new
如果您想建立一个新的
micro service let's say this is
微服务，我们说这是
something worth considering
值得考虑的事情
watch our two DBC progress if you are
观看我们两个DBC的进度，如果您
considering maybe going into really
考虑也许真的
reactive applications and that's
反应性应用程序，那就是
something that I definitely use test
我肯定使用测试的东西
containers only if you can if your build
容器只有在您可以的情况下
server supports spinning up docker
服务器支持旋转docker
containers use test containers it will
容器使用测试容器
solve lots of your testing test related
解决很多与测试有关的测试
issues thank you very much
问题非常感谢你
these are all the links that you can
这些都是您可以链接的
find the stuff about me I tweet quite a
找到关于我的东西，我在推特上
lot sometimes too much and and and then
很多，有时太多，然后
I have to delete them and this
我必须删除它们
presentation will be posted soon on the
演示文稿将很快发布在
on the speaker deck that I've also tweet
在我也发推文的扬声器甲板上
about so yeah so thank you all for
关于，所以谢谢大家
coming it it was
来了
a pleasure to speak with you to speak to
很高兴与您交谈
you thank you and I will be around like
你谢谢你，我会像
four questions and so on
四个问题，依此类推
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]